Once upon a time, many years ago, there was a happy prince.
He recalled no painful past and knew no painful future.
One day, the prince obtained a comforting warmth.
The source of this warmth, however, emanated not only tranquility,
but also unhappiness, pain, and loneliness.
What are you reading?
Nothing. It's none of your business.
The prince and the raven, huh? I see.
What?
Seems you've gained an interest in seeing Muto as he was in the story, back before he lost his heart.
Are you implying I'm the one restoring Muto's heart?
Am I wrong, then?
Hold it!
What's so funny?
What would you do if Princess Tutu really existed?
Did something happen?
No, nothing happened.
Yes, that's right. Elongage your spine.
Hey, Duck, made up your mind yet? About what?
Huh?
What?
Did you forget what's going on today?
Um, I guess I did.
Huh?
The fire festival.
The what now?
Don't you remember? We're asking if you've decided what you're going to wear to the festival.
So, what's this fire festival again?
It's okay, Duck. It's okay.
Even if you lack any common sense living in this town and not knowing about the fire festival,
you're just so darn cute.
Because I'm just a bird to begin with.
Miss Duck.
Yeah, yeah. So I'm a duck.
Miss Duck!
I know already.
I get it. Tell me about the fire festival.
Oh!
Very well, I'll tell you.
Y-yes, sir.
The fire festival is a town set where folks dress in the old ways and dance round a bonfire.
I see, then. I think I understand it now.
But most important of all is the golden apple given to the couple who dances the most exquisitely at the event.
Golden apple?
That's right. It's said that the couple to whom the golden apple is given will be bound together forever.
Bound together forever? But that's nothing to do with me.
Miss Duck.
Right, because I'm a duck.
Miss Duck!
But that's okay. I know it.
I said I know that!
Oh. I'm so sorry.
Miss Duck!
As punishment for your lack of focus, you will clean the advanced classes lesson room.
If you don't do it properly, I will have you marry me!
Then you'll come with me to the quiet place for now.
Yes, because if you win the apple by some fluke, you'll be bound.
Mewtwo.
I told him not to leave without asking.
The golden apple, huh?
Try not to forget now.
The princess who saves the prince is fated never to be with her dearly beloved.
I don't care.
Mewtwo.
He's a prince.
Is this the real you, Mewtwo?
Try not to forget now.
As soon as you confess your love, you'll turn into a speck of light and vanish.
Uh, uh, uh, that is, I'm on cleaning duty as punishment, so please don't mind me.
Have you seen Rue anywhere?
Seen Rue?
Rue said she wanted to practice dancing for the fire festival, so I've been waiting here all day.
Oh, so Muto's going to be dancing with Rue tonight, of course.
When I'm alone, it feels so dark and cold.
Feelings?
Will you be going tonight, Duck?
He just called me by name.
Come, Duck, let's dance.
Muto! I can't go to the fire festival!
Muto wanted, Muto wanted to dance of his own will.
Could it be because he's regaining his heart?
If it is, I'd be happy.
Ah, ah, ah, ah.
Her again.
Damn.
Ah, ah, please, excuse me.
Ah!
Ah, ah!
I can't believe it.
I danced with Muto the Prince.
Ha, ha, ha.
Ah, ah.
Ah, ah, ah, ah, ah.
Have you seen Rue anywhere?
That was in Rue's place.
Ah.
She practically is a duck.
Hey!
That voice just now...
I knew it was him.
What's the meaning of this?
What?
Dressed in this silly outfit.
Bruce said to wear it.
Listen, all you have to do is obey my orders and don't pay any heed to what anyone else tells you.
That includes what Rue says.
So you were dancing?
Yes.
What's with that duck-like girl that I've seen scurrying around lately?
Duck-like? Well, I am a duck, but...
She's called Duck. Her name is Duck.
I didn't ask for trivia.
There's no need to dance with the likes of her just because she asked.
That's not what happened.
Rue hadn't come.
And I'd been waiting by myself.
Then Duck came so...
Are you saying you invited her to dance?
Yes.
Don't make me repeat myself.
All you have to do is listen to what I tell you and stop wasting your time on such useless nonsense.
I can't hear.
When you were wandering aimlessly, completely stripped of all your memories, I was the one who gave you the name of Muto.
I'm the one who saved you and don't ever forget that.
Hm.
You will stay home.
Got it?
Being as you are now is for the best.
But Rue...
wants me to dance with her.
Forget about Rue!
I have to let her know I can't go.
Are you defying me?
No, but...
Come with me!
Where are we going, Fakir?
Fakir?
Never mind that!
The library?
No, I can't go.
Fine...
Go!
Hobful doing.
And look!
Slimping peers
But yet, Fakir took Muto away.
Anyway, I have to go back to being Duck the Girl....
Water...
Water!
Go!
U tak alliance to build a unicorn in Intel森.
Fakir?
Yes!
Roo.
Doc.
So, you're meeting up with Muto, right?
How do you know that?
Well, you see, the truth is, I was kind of put on cleaning duty as punishment,
so I was in here cleaning not too long ago, and Muto was here too,
and he said he was going to practice dancing with you.
Wow, it's totally wet over here.
Of course, I'm the one who made the mess.
So where's Muto?
Oh, I think he stepped out for a bit.
What, you didn't go chase him down like you did the other day?
Oh, well…
And then you suddenly disappeared for some reason.
Yeah, sorry.
If you happen to see Muto, please tell him I'll be going on ahead to the square.
Oh, okay.
Hey Roo, Muto will come and find you, I'm sure he will.
You're like a real princess, and you really suit each other,
so I'm sure you'll get the golden apple too.
I know they went in the library for sure, but…
Stay there and behave yourself.
Why?
Punishment.
I'm sorry.
Don't be mad, Fakir.
I'll do as you say.
Fakir, I'll do as you say.
Fakir, I…
What are you doing?
Punishment.
Why do you always do such terrible things?
What are you doing?
Punishment.
Why do you always do such terrible things?
And you, Muto, Roo's waiting for you.
You finally have some shards of your heart back now.
What are you doing?
You don't have to listen to him anymore.
Shards of his heart?
What are you doing?
You don't have to listen to him anymore.
Shards of his heart?
Your name's Duck, right?
Just what do you know?
N-nothing.
What are you doing?
I'm sorry.
Don't be mad, Fakir.
I'll do as you say.
Fakir, I…
What are you doing?
Punishment!
Punishment.
Why do you always do such terrible things?
And you, Muto, Roo's waiting for you.
You finally have some shards of your heart back now.
You don't have to listen to him anymore.
Shards of his heart?
Your name's Duck, right?
Just what do you know?
N-nothing, really.
Come to think of it, you asked me about the Prince and the Raven that one time.
You know, don't you?
You know that Muto is actually a prince from inside a story.
Did Roo tell you?
Roo?
Roo and this person both know Muto's secret?
Muto has no need of a heart.
Huh?
Has no need of a heart?
What are you saying?
There's no way!
And just what do you know?
I know everything about Muto.
What do you know?
Well, sure, I may not know anything about Muto, but if he's missing his heart,
he won't know how it feels to be happy or be in love either.
That's why…
Forget it.
Even if he regains shards of his heart, I'll seal him away.
If I shut him away in the darkness, he'll become numb even to the dark.
Numb to all sensation, he'll stop feeling altogether.
That's just… that's just terrible of you!
Don't let your ignorance carry you away.
Acting so high and mighty, like he knows everything.
When I gave Muto back his heart and shards, he thanked me.
He did!
Are you afraid of the dark?
You'll be okay.
But it's true.
I don't know anything, not when it comes to Muto.
Am I sticking my nose where it doesn't belong?
Are you afraid of the dark?
I see you're in the darkness of uncertainty.
But if you wish to shine for someone,
you must not fear the darkness.
I see. You mean I shouldn't fear what I don't understand.
Right?
A path is open to you.
What? He's not here?
Mewto, where did you go?
Guh!
This is what it looks like under the library?
Oh...it's a hard shard!
Who's there? Mewtwo?
Are you there?
I'm just a little thing, but I flood the entire room.
What am I?
A riddle?
It's coming from the other side.
I mustn't fear the darkness.
Okay, just a little thing that floods the entire room.
Oh, a sneeze!
Too bad.
I'm a white snake that swallows the sea.
What am I?
Um, a white paintbrush with red paint on it?
Too bad.
Here's the last one.
I become shorter the longer I stand.
What am I?
So you're like a flower, right?
Too bad.
But congratulations.
The person you're looking for is here.
What, Muto?
Give him back!
No.
You also are to stay here.
I can't do that!
You'll be fine.
I'm here.
Who are you?
Oh, dear, oh, dear.
Are you to become a prisoner of the darkness now and forever?
Or will you be able to rekindle your radiance, Princess Tutu?
Are you there?
Who are you?
I am Princess Tutu.
You're wonderful.
Please stay and dance.
I'll illuminate you for the rest of your life.
Illuminate me?
That's right.
So that's it.
The little thing that floods the entire room is the light of a lamp, then.
And the white snake with the red head that swallows the sea and becomes shorter the longer it stands is the lamp's wick.
You're a lamp, am I right?
You are correct.
Now please give back Muto and his heart.
No.
Idiot.
Please dance with me.
Dance with you?
Yes.
You dance.
I will light your steps.
Your light is so warm and gentle.
Why are you doing this?
What do you want?
My one wish.
My only wish is to keep on shining for someone.
I want to envelop them tenderly in warm light.
Wanting to shine for someone.
That was all.
I didn't want anything else.
And yet, somewhere along the way, I had simply become forgotten.
The people who are precious to me forgot about me and the light I gave them.
No.
They must not have needed me from the beginning.
That can't be true.
I thought they enjoyed my presence.
But that was only what I believed.
I'm sure that's not true.
But right now, there is someone who wants my light.
Muto.
Is that what you want?
To shut him away?
Yes.
I will stay here and illuminate him for all time.
Please, remember what it was like to have your warm light shine on the people you love.
I haven't forgotten.
Then you should know.
Forcing your warmth on people won't bring joy to anyone.
I love the soft and tender glow of your warm light.
I believe that the people who were precious to you were very happy to have you envelop them with that glow.
It's sad that they no longer need you.
But it's something that can't be helped.
Because it isn't something that you can force on people.
If you want what is best for Muto, return his heart.
That will bring him happiness.
Will it?
It's what I believe.
Princess Tutu.
I want to continue illuminating you.
I am the feeling of affection, shattered and forgotten.
The feeling of affection?
Return to Muto now.
Muto.
Princess Tutu.
You should hurry now.
Huh?
Someone is waiting for you.
I was such a fool for believing what Dax said.
Muto.
The fire festival ended long ago.
Sorry.
Muto, what are you doing?
Muto?
Stop it.
You're acting strange.
This is how it should be.
For such kindness to be in your eyes, it's…
Ryo…
The Prince regained the feeling of happiness, but has it illuminated Duck's unhappiness?
Love? It's really not anything like that with me.
I'm sure she's pursuing a wonderful dream, and chances are she's also in love.
You'll always wake up from a dream.
No, you must wake up.
What's this?
You're trembling.
I'm afraid of Princess Tutu.
I just wanted Mewtwo to smile.
That's all I wanted.
Have I just done something terrible to Mewtwo?
All who love stories gather round.
Thank you.